Welcome back to New Orleans Football
presented by Loft 18. Great show for you
guys today. The big draft recap. The
Saints have their draft class in place.
Things are taking shape and we are about
to find out soon enough what the Saints
are going to be in this upcoming season.
Going to be really exciting to see how
Jordan Tyson fits and the rest of this
class. So, we're going to be breaking
that down on today's show. Uh get you
caught up with all that. And if you want
to get caught up with a little bit of
fun now that the draft's over, Loft 18
is the place to do it. They got four
locations. Meet Mandavville, Brousard,
Baton Rouge, go through there, hang out,
have a good time, watch an LSU baseball
game, whatever you got to do, they will
get you right. They will get you into a
a good time. Tell them that NOFF sent
you and uh enjoy the drink specials. And
if you're going there, do it in the car
that you buy from my guy Matt Bowers,
best car dealer in the whole entire
galaxy. Check him out at one of his many
locations. Uh we got a great show for
you guys today. We're going to get into
all of that and we're going to get
started off here with our first topic
presented by PJs because we start every
single day with PJs and you should too.
Saints got their draft class. Uh let's
start at the top. Jordan Tyson. They get
Jordan Tyson. They make that pick. He's
on the team now. Um we talked about a
little bit on the last show, but few
days removed. You're looking at that
depth chart completely remade. They
actually released Samari Tore today
because it's filled out now. Just a
whole new cache of weapons for Tyler
Shuck.
>> Yeah, Elijah Cook's released too. He he
joined at the end of last year. It's so
funny how many guys they were adding to
that room late last season and throwing
into games. Yeah, I mean it's you know
Bryce Lance is now there. Uh um you know
the the Brown from LSU will probably be
primarily a kick returner, but I do you
know you wonder what what happens to
Jaylen P. What happens to Mason Typton?
What happens to Kevin Austin? Guys we
were uh thinking could have real roles
on this team. But I mean it just makes
over the position. It makes over the
offense. Makes over the identity of the
team. Um it it it's crazy how I think we
talked a lot leading up to the draft.
maybe went back and forth on whether
wide receiver or pass rusher was the
biggest need for this team, but either
way, it was number one or number two.
And now all of a sudden, the draft is
over and it feels like the strength of
the team. I mean, it's certainly the
speed, certainly the big play ability,
uh certainly the touchdown catching
ability, not only because you add Jordan
Tyson and Bryce Lance, but now you feel
so much better about Chris Alav and
Devon Ble. They're not going to be asked
to do too much. Chris Alav might see,
you know, single teams. He might see
number two cornerbacks. U obviously
Devon Ble will see a lot less attention.
It's just um very excited to see Jordan
Tyson, but even more so like very
excited to see this passing game. Jawan
Johnson will see less, you know,
attention. I mean, it's just like all of
a sudden when you add the most dynamic
presence uh that you can get in the
draft to a position group, it makes the
whole position group that much deeper,
that much better.
>> I don't even know who's going to be on
this, like you said, I I I don't know
who's going to be on this team next year
because I think obviously obviously
Jordan Tyson, Chris Lave, uh Bryce Lance
is, you know, you aren't guaranteed
anything as a fourth round pick, but
fourth round picks usually make your
team. So, there's three right there.
Devon Bailey is going to make the team.
That's four. If Barry and Brown is your
returner, I mean, they drafted him for
that role. He's probably on the team
that's five. I guess you could earmark
Barry and Brown as like a special teams
addition. And then you're looking for
and maybe there's another one, but
somebody's not going to be here. And
that there's some names there like you
you said, Mason Typton's been around for
a few years. You really definitely got
to wonder what happens to him. Bryce
Lance felt like maybe a strike at him a
little bit. uh just being that faster
guy that can get down the field. But
Jaylen Pulk now, we kind of probably
would have had him on the roster as damn
near like a yes before the draft. Now
it's a it's a maybe and it's not a
definitely maybe. It's a maybe. Trey
Palmer, uh don't know where that one's
going to go. Yeah, I mean, so so there's
definitely guys uh Bub Means might be
the end of the road for him. There's
some guys here with with names and hope
that used to be attached to him that I
don't know that there's a spot for him
on the team now. And
>> poor
>> Kevin poor Kevin Austin like he finally
got his chance last year and he
delivered on it and it's like well maybe
there's another team that's going to
have to give him a chance. I actually
like this Damen Alford they signed from
Canada like we're never going to see a
good problem
>> forgot about him.
>> Uh good problem to have for this team.
Obviously, one thing I will say about
Bryce Lance though is um Mickey Lumis
did say when he came at the end of the
draft, like right away when he was
talking about the receiver position as a
whole, he made a point that he came from
North Dakota State and and you know said
so he'll probably be a little bit more
of a developmental guy. It's it's
definitely possible that Bryce Lance
ends up in that like healthy and active
every week, red shirt year or a red
shirt first two months of the season
while some of the other guys we're
talking about are are playing more and
then Lance gets his opportunity when
somebody gets hurt inevitably or
something like that. So, it could be a
keep seven receivers knowing that that
he's going to be sort of the red shirt
early in the season, but who knows?
Maybe he'll he'll light it up in in camp
and and make himself inevitable. But it
is crazy how how much they have to
choose from.
>> Look, if Bryce Lance can run 43 down the
field when they go in 13 personnel and
they get the safeties biting down and
they hit play action and and that's all
he can do, he has a spot on my team.
That's all I need him to do. Um,
>> and it kind of looks like they're going
that direction, too. Uh, let's just go
going through the draft class right
here. They took Jordan Tyson in the
first round, Kristen Miller, the
defensive tackle out of Georgia in the
second. Got another Bulldog in the
third, Oscar Delp. Fourth, Jeremiah
Wright. Fourth round, Bryce Lance. They
traded a uh a fifth for Tyrie Wilson. Uh
drafted Lorenzo Styles Jr. in the fifth.
Barry Brown, the wide receiver from LSU,
and then TJ Hall, the Iowa cornerback,
uh was their final pick of the draft.
Yeah, look, it's definitely offense. And
it's funny that they went this route.
They drafted three freaking wide
receivers uh and a tight end. And every
time we were doing a mock draft, it was
like, man, like I kind of want to take
this other receiver later on, but I
don't think they will. That might be
>> different.
>> It might be doing too much. And they
kind of just said, you know what,
building the offense in free agency,
building the offense in the draft. I
don't know that they set in with this
goal, but the opportunities played out
like that. But they build a team now
where they have a obvious strength of
the roster and if they're going to win
games, it's going to be because they're
able to score points. Now, um, you know,
I I I know that might feel a little
disrespectful to a defense that ended up
finishing top 10 last year in pretty
much every type of metric you want to
use to measure it in overall efficiency.
Um, but it's definitely an offensive
team and and look, I I like I know where
they finish, but I I have a little bit
of little bit of pause about what the
defense is going to be next year, but
going to the second round pick, I do
feel like Kristen Miller, I don't know
that they set out again their designs. I
I don't know that it was we're going to
get a great run stuffing defensive
tackle with the 42nd pick in the draft.
I I think the run on pass rushers right
before they came on the clock probably
changed their plans, but I like this
addition quite a bit. I He He My
favorite thing about him is if you look
at his trajectory, like the last three
years playing three years ago, average
depth to tackle was 2.7 yards. This year
it was 1.5 for a team that allowed 120
rushing yards per game. I think it's a
really good pick.
>> Yeah, it's interesting. Um, I think we
thought our Mason Thomas might be the
target there and he went what, like two
picks before. Um, the Saints didn't
necessarily say they pivoted. They did
say they tried to trade up on that day
unsuccessfully, but they said what it
came down to with Kristen Miller is they
agreed in their room that there this was
not a good draft for big men and that it
was going to be hard to find big men.
And so they pounced on the opportunity
to get one, you know, in particular on
the defensive line. Like that that's
something they thought there wasn't a
lot of depth, they couldn't get later.
Um, and they loved the value of that. So
if he ends up, you know, if that ends up
being like where you mind value out of
this draft where you couldn't get it
later, then it's a smart pick. I mean,
is he going to be a game changer? Is he
going to turn into a guy who like
develops into an eight sack guy? Is he
going to just be the assist leader? I
remember when Sheldon Rankings, they
used to call him Chris Paul because all
the edge rushers got to eat because he
was there. That that would help this
defensive line too, just as much as the
edge rusher. They and then they had
Tyrie Wilson later and and Anthony
Jennings a day later. So, they have a
depth of options if if the interior
opens things up for those guys that can
help the pass rush, too. Even if he
himself is not the pass rusher.
>> Yeah, I think if he's an assist maker,
it probably be a little bit different
than like the shot. like it'll probably
be more like a eat and blocks type
thing. I I don't think he's ever going
to be a a great penetrator, pass rusher
type player. I I think he's probably
more like he's a big guy, can get a
little bit of push. Um but I, you know,
I think I think he's the the
you have to have this type of player.
And then you have Vernon Brown who who
would be the the Sheldon Rankings get in
there, make a play type player. Brian
Baz is more of a pass rushing DT. I
think Kristen Miller's more in the Devon
Gotcha type build. Um, which they need
though. They're a three- four defense.
And again, it's a huge massive need. And
if you draft a DT at 42, who ends up
with two sacks a season, I don't know,
that's always like the the
guy you focus in on for the next six
months, we're probably going to talk
about Kristen Miller a couple times and
then probably won't again for a while.
>> You will let their run defense improves
because
>> that's exactly it. one of the areas of
this team that needed improving most and
if their run defense gets better, we'll
talk about it a lot.
>> Exactly. I I'm just saying like the hype
up to the season, it's like, yeah, they
got a guy that can stop their own.
That's like they needed it. It's a huge
need. It's going to improve the team a
lot, but we're going to probably spend
the next four or five months talking
about Jordan Tyson and Oscar Delp and
Bryce Lance and Barry and that's just
the way it is. But then on October 10th
when you're watching him, you know, not
give up 120 yards and you're not sitting
there in despair feeling like the
defense is helpless and getting
manhandled is going to be because of him
and they need that. I I think it was a
quietly really big need. We were super
excited about Devon Godshaw last year
cuz we thought he was going to be that
type of player and I think he helped a
little bit at times but I don't know
that it brought the consistency all the
way. I think when you draft this type of
player at 42, it's with a strong bet on
that. And the one thing I like about
him, um, and throughout history during
the draft, when you when you get texts
from scouts from other teams and they're
like, "Damn, I like that pick." That
usually ends up being a good player.
Like Kristen Miller was that guy. Like
it wasn't the other people in this
draft. Kristen Miller was the one where
it was like, "Damn, that's a good pick."
So, I I like it. I like it just on uh on
that merit. Continuing this
conversation,
>> that sounds like you're talking about a
consensus board. But I don't believe in
that name.
>> Continuing this conversation presented
by the mortgage bros. Mortgage
bros.money. If you are buying a house,
they will save you uh they'll give you
500 bucks back on your closing cost if
you tell them that I've sent you. If
you're buying a house, you might as well
do that. They're working for you. They
aren't a bank. They're going to try to
get you uh into the house of your
dreams, and they don't get paid unless
you get your house. So, go check them
out. Really good guys, comfortable guys.
They were out at our draft event last
week. Um had a good time uh catching up
with them. Um, yeah. Continuing this
one.
I don't know if I if I'm like too deep
in the, you know, I don't know if I'm
like trying to do like the the the alt
take here or whatever. I'm really
excited about the Oscar Delt pick.
>> You need to convince me. You you you
need to convince me. And I'm not saying
I don't like the pick. Actually, a lot
of people love this pick. But convince
me as if I'm the guy who wasn't sitting
next to you and you haven't already
convinced me. But I mean, when you look
at him, no stats at Georgia, barely at
all. And then he's a pass catcher first
with with uh with the ability to like
get better as a blocker. So, it's like
he's not a blocking first tight end. He
ran a 4.49. And when you watch his
highlights, you're like, "Oh my god,
this guy probably caught 70 passes last
year." He didn't. Um, but it seems like
universally everyone just knows he's a
guy and and Georgia Georgia was holding
him back with their sort of simple uh
we're going to win every game 20 to7
anyway so we don't need to light it up
offense.
>> Yeah. So I I went and watched them twice
this year and like I don't I you know I
hadn't done a lot of like box score
scouting on um on on you know Oscar Delp
at that point. like I had just gone out
and I watched him. Um I seen him at the
Sugar Bowl and then I seen the I was
there for the uh Georgia Texas game and
I'm looking right now to even see what
he did in that game cuz I I don't even
remember what the stats were. But both
times like I went and watched them. It's
just one of them things where you're
kind of like watching the game and your
eye keeps going to him and it's like oh
man they got another one like you know
it's just kind of like the way he moves
and everything. Yeah,
>> he had three for 36 that game. Uh
catcher 23 yards, but like just the way
he moves, the way he runs his routes,
you're watching, you're like, damn, they
got another tight end. Like they just
always do this. And then, you know, as
the drafts going on, you're looking at
like he only had 200 and some yards this
year. Like, it just didn't didn't quite
add up. So, I think the athlete to me,
just the way he moved caught my eye, and
I and I thought he looked pretty good.
Um,
you know, I think he he's a very strong
and willing blocker and the way they use
him, I I don't know that it necessarily
shows up in
I don't even know what his numbers are
there, like the PFF scores or whatever
it is, but they're going to put him on
an edge against an SEC pass rusher, guys
that go to the NFL, and they're going to
trust him to block him when you go
through and you you watch their tape,
which is different than, oh, he's out in
space throwing a block, you know, or,
oh, he's in the, you the the you know
the SEC is just different like these are
the guys that are in the league. they're
they're Sunday players like they're
trusting him to do stuff against them
which you know obviously sometimes those
numbers are going to be a little bit
different but when you look at it and
you actually quantify the stats or
whatever I think I think that changes
too but even beyond that I don't think
it's look I think he can do everything
and I think if you can find a tight end
that can actually catch the ball at a
plus level and block at a plus level
it's it's the biggest cheat code in the
NFL and I think it's even more so now
we're we're looking at a league that a
team just won the the the the the title
with lesser talent off a superior scheme
and a scheme that kind of took advantage
of everyone. And this plays into my
whole thing. Like I I just think that
there's a not a proper valuing of
safeties, linebackers, tight ends, and
running backs in the NFL right now
because the league's going to 12 and 13
personnel, which is, you know, two tight
ends, three tight end sets. And I think
they have three now. They have three of
these guys. The Rams were really good
last year playing a lot of 13 personnel.
I don't know that the Saints are going
to go all the way into 13 personnel, but
I think Oscar Delp's a guy that can do
so much that you can put him in a bunch
of these different spots with multiple
tight ends on the field, which allows
you to put your other guys in other
spots and his placement on the field
isn't a tell. Jack Stole rolls out there
last year. Ah they're they're
running the ball. You know, like I don't
think you feel that way right now. So I
think you can go out there in these
multi-look sets, no off gives you a
little bit of that, too. And it isn't a
tell and it allows you to kind of maybe
put guys in different places and dictate
matchups and now you can put Dell Pier
and you can move Fan over here and you
can put Jawan over here if you're in 13
and you can still run the ball or you
could just maybe have this really great
mismatch that you're dictating now and
it makes it much more difficult to
defend. So, I just even think beyond all
that, just a high value, highlevel tight
end that it does enough that makes you
respect everything opens up your offense
in a way that that it wouldn't if you
didn't have them. Like, you can go to 13
personnel, but if you don't have the
tight ends to do it, I think it it it
creates issues for your team. They were
even solid and 13 last year with the
tight ends they had. But look, it was
the lowest amount of 12 that Callum
Moore has ever had in his whole entire
career. Normally, he's like around 22
25%. They were at 15.9 last year. In
Philly, he was almost at 30 because he
had Dallas Scott. But you you look at
you look at that and it just tells you
that Collins looking at his group of
tight ends and being like, nah, like
this group isn't very good. I'm not I'm
not playing like this. I'm going to be
in 11 most of the time, three wide
receivers because I don't feel like I
have the tight ends. I think now he
feels like he has the tight ends. I
think he's going to take liberally from
the Rams, from Seattle. Uh the Falcons
were a pretty good 12 team last year.
Like I think I think they're he's going
to take stuff from that. I think we're
going to see a completely different
offense. We're going to see a great set
of wide receivers. We're going to see a
great set of tight ends. We're going to
see an improved run game. I think he has
everything now. And this is a creative
coach. And I think he can just scheme
all over the place. So it isn't even
just necessarily what Oscar Delp does
for the team. It's what Oscar Delp does
for the scheme for their ability to do
things. I it's it's not even necessarily
all of it is attached to him. While I
like the player, I think just the idea
of having a tight end that's worth a
third round pick um that can do both
things decently well. Uh I think it just
opens up your team so much more.
>> And Kell Moore talked about that uh uh
pretty excitedly when he was talking
about, you know, learning from the
models of the NFL and the Seahawks and
what they just did last year. There's no
question what motivated uh this move and
and they weren't alone. Uh if like I
don't know where Delp was projected to
go in this draft or whatever, but tight
ends all went about a rounder. It was a
run on tight ends. It's a copycat league
and we saw that in this draft for sure.
One one last question about the offense.
One last question about one of their
premium draft picks they made. Um did
they improve their offensive line by
drafting Jeremiah Wright or you think
we're a year away or an injury away from
seeing him on the field? Is he pushing
Caesar Ruiz or not this year, next year?
>> Jeremiah Wright's interesting to me and
uh this conversation's continued by
Hardh High Punch Strawberry Whiskey and
uh Chilton County Peach. Jeremiah Wright
is really interesting to me because I
think he has a lot of room to get I
think he has a lot of room to improve.
Uh former defensive tackle hasn't been
playing the position that long. Um,
I like that he wins by being big kind
of, and I also think that means there's
room for for technique to come behind it
and maybe make him a uh a guy with an
arrow pointing up. But I think the
development aspect of it is going to
have to come with it as well for for him
to to push Caesar off. I I don't I don't
know that I see it right away, but I
could see it in time for sure. I think
you take him in the fourth round because
you think that there's the ability for
him to continue to get better and
improve and and become that type of
player, but I think he's in a good spot
because there's opportunity for him if
he if he can take it, but he also isn't
being counted on to take it right away.
So, I I like I like the pick there and
that idea. It is a little bit higher
than a lot of people projected him. I
know there was another team out there
that had him, you know, quite a bit
ranked differently and um, you know,
we'll kind of see how it goes with him,
but I I like the idea of him. I like how
he moves. I like how he plays and I like
that that there's kind of some uh, you
know, on form clay there with him. And
it's a pick that even if he isn't a
starter, if he can become a really good
backup, I I think that would be good for
him. But I also feel like Lumis kind of
said the same thing uh a bit after the
draft when he was asked about his inside
out ability or could he could he play
center and guard and Mickey said they'd
be doing him a disservice if they asked
him to do more than guard right now. I
think that kind of tells you that
they're looking at him that way as if he
needs to to just kind of focus on the
craft, get better, and I think he's in a
great spot to do that. Well, the other
thing that's interesting is they didn't
address center, but it lends even more
credence to what we were talking about
during the NOFF event. I can't remember
if we talked about this on the air or
not or at Loft 18 or just when we were
having conversations with the people
that came out that night. Right now,
Caesar Ruiz is my backup center on this
team. if Eric McCoy is gonna miss more
than a game or a half. Uh if if Eric
McCoy would ever miss a month or eight
weeks or anything like that because now
you've got Dylan Raidens and now you've
got Jeremiah right like you've got defin
um um and I think Caesar Ruiz has played
his best football at center. So uh I I
wonder if they're picturing uh the same
thing, but yeah, I think Ruiz is is
written in ink as the starting right
guard right now.
>> We talked about Bryce Lance already. I'm
I'm excited about his explosiveness and
what he can do and what he brings to the
team. I I I felt like they got him, man,
like way lower than than I was expecting
him to go. Uh I think on on our uh mock
drafts, like he he was a third round
pick consistently, so he didn't end up
in our range of like, man, should should
they take this guy that was shribbling
who uh
>> who set off a complete firestorm on the
internet? We'll get to that uh in the
next block. Uh, holy crap. But then the
next two picks and I I love that they
went here, man. Like it felt like fifth
round, sixth round was special teams
going to get you the gunner that you
lost uh when JT Gray was cut and and
Yonas Anker became a huge part of the
defense. Lorenzo Styles, Junior, Sunny's
brother, 43 speed, 42 speed rather. Uh
he's going to be awesome on special
teams right off the bat. We'll kind of
see where it goes from there. Can return
a little bit too. I saw that at Ohio
State. Um, so multiaceted there and then
also has the ability to potentially
develop and become a player on defense.
So I like the upside. I like the
athleticism, the RA score, all that
stuff. And then Barry and Brown,
probably the best returner in this this
entire class. Uh, if he's not, he's he's
in that conversation. So two guys on
special teams, big investment there.
They signed Mason Shipley, the Texas
kicker, afterward to compete with
Charlie Smith. just signed Ryan Wright
uh the punter. Just a remade special
teams completely
an admission allowed admission that they
didn't have the players there last year.
>> Yeah, no question. And yeah, Barry
Brown, look, we did that was one of the
few that we nailed from uh previous mock
drafts. I mean, we were joking about
letting Phil Galliano have the room for
for day three and identified Barry Brown
as probably the best kick returner in
this draft. Usually they like to find
the undrafted guy from a college you've
never heard of. This time they went for
the guy who had six career kickoff
return touchdowns of 99 or 100 yards.
Six. Um while at Kentucky and LSU,
that's your kick returner. I don't know
if he's your punt returner as well.
Hell, Lorenzo Styles could also be your
punt returner. I think Lorenzo Styles
has like the highest RA score ever. They
they went from like, "Oh, this team
drafts guys with high RA scores to like
topping themselves this year with like
three guys that are just off the charts
with their RA scores." And yeah, Lorenzo
Styles ran the 40 in 4.27 seconds, but
he was hurt. So, he's really more of a
4.22 guy.
>> Yeah. Unbelievable, man. And
>> a real kicker battle, too. I mean, they
they they got a real one in here.
Charlie Charlie is going to have to
continue to prove he is developing and
that he, you know, has ice water in his
veins and all those things that it's not
too big for him cuz they brought in real
competition for him.
>> And then it doesn't mean anything, but
man, Barry and Brown like his uh post
pick media availability I think is my
favorite one of all time, man. Just like
the joy and excitement in that was just
maybe the it was like the purest thing
ever. It's like this is why this is why
we're all here. this is why we all watch
the game. This is why we cover it. This
is why they play it. Like his reaction
right there was just it it was just like
so so so pure, man. It was it was it was
kind of it was really awesome. If you
haven't seen that video, check it out on
our uh website or our uh YouTube
channel. And then topping it out,
finishing the draft, TJ Hall, Iowa, one
of your guys, uh cornerback,
four five speed. I you know, when you
watch him, I I I just spent a little bit
of time this morning getting caught up
on him. one of like the smartest man. He
sees everything. Like if he was if he
was a little bit faster, he would have
been like people would have been
climbing over themselves to to get him.
>> I'm interested to see what he can do. I
I think his instincts can can I I think
they give him a shot. I really do. I
think his instincts give him a shot to
do something.
>> No question. I mean, yeah, he he I just
mentioned RA score. They they they went
the complete opposite direction with
him. He's all football tape. Uh, you
know, I think he won the hustle award at
Iowa. That's not an insult. That's an
actual award they have. He was, you
know, quarterback on the defense,
captain on the field, potentially a guy
who would play your star nickel
position, hybrid, safety, corner, uh,
nickel, dime, special teams. Yeah, he's
going to get himself on the field that
way more than run a 4.240.
>> All right, we're going to hit a quick
break. We're going to keep talking about
the draft and what it means for next
season right after this.
>> Welcome to Loft 18, your favorite local
sports bar.
The economyy's been tough and
entertainment hasn't been as affordable
as it once was. We get it. That's why
we're changing the whole game with lower
menu prices, all new deals, and brand
new promotions.
Great service, good vibes, and
consistent food. Here at Loft 18, the
experience is built around you.
Rouse's Markets is voted best grocery
store in New Orleans, best grocery store
in Baton Rouge, Mississippi, GF Coast,
Tibido, Homa, Hammond, Lake Charles,
Mobile year after year. Thank you for
choosing us. Best grocery store on the
Gulf Coast. Number one. Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> The number one grocery store
>> in Mississippi, Alabama, Louisiana. A
million customers a week can't be wrong.
Welcome to Rouses. Here
at New Orleans Football, we get every
day started with PJs and you should too.
We are proud to be partnered with them.
They have the best coffee, the best
pastries and locations all over the city
and state. PJ's Coffee, check them out.
Get your day started with them. There's
a ton of great things about living in
New Orleans, but one of the worst things
about living in New Orleans is the
soaring insurance cost. Whether it's
your house, your flood, your car,
somebody's always trying to get in your
pocket, somebody's always trying to
raise prices. That's why you need a
partner like Shaw Air Insurance, the
Airheart Agency to have your back. Every
six months, I get a call from them. Hey,
look, your car insurance is going up.
This is what we can do to lower it. Do
you want to do it? Yeah, of course I
want to do it. Same thing when my home
insurance comes up. Hey, do you want to
bring this price down? Yes, I want to
bring my price down. They're watching it
so I don't have to. Somebody's trying to
get deeper in my pockets, they're
stopping people from getting deeper into
my pockets. You need people like that
because it means money in your pockets.
So, do business with Shaw Bear
Insurance, the Airheart Agency. Make
sure you're looking for the Airheart
Agency branch. That's the one we use.
They look out for me. I use them long
before they ever advertised on this
podcast. They save me money. They'll
save you money. Tell them I've sent you.
You ever take a bite of something and
immediately think, "Yeah, I'm coming
back for this." Bobby Aber's Cajun
Cannon Restaurant just added some new
dishes, and man, they crushed it. The
shrimp and crawfish pistollettes, golden
and stuffed with bold Cajun flavor.
Fried oyster tacos, crispy, fresh with
the perfect kick. And the soft shell
crab alfredo, creamy, rich, and
absolutely worth the order. They're open
7 days a week and they deliver late.
Bobby Aber's Cajun Cannon Restaurant.
Delicious food, superior service. New
Orleans do football is proud to be in
business with our longtime partners at
Hardh High Punch Strawberry Whiskey and
Chilton County Peach. When you're out
and about in your favorite stores, your
favorite bars, your favorite
restaurants, look up on the shelf, look
for the red bottle. Look for the orange
bottle. See if there's a gator on it. If
there is, that's your drink. It's going
to taste right. It's going to get you
right. Look for hardhide in your
favorite stores, bars, and restaurants.
Welcome back to New Orleans Top Football
presented by Loft 18. four locations,
Mandaville, Meety, Baton Rouge, and
Bruce. Go check them out. Hit some golf
balls, play some zombie dodgeball,
whatever you want to do. Uh, they got
you. All right, next one. Presented by
Bobby Abear's Cajun Cannon Restaurant.
They got the draft. You've been Mr.
Negative. Eight wins before the draft.
The draft's over. They got Jordan Tyson,
Chris Miller, Oscar Delp, Jeremiah
Wright, Bryce Lance, Sorenzo Styles,
Tyrie Wilson, Barryian Brown, TJ Hall.
Has your win total moved?
>> I don't think so. I don't think so.
>> Oh, no.
>> I think I'm still eight and nine, but
I'm eight and nine because I know what's
going to happen to this team. I know I
know, you know, some of their star
players are going to miss six games and
eight games and and like I I just still
think they're a year away from the
depth. I love two draft classes in a
row. They've added uh if you include
Tyrie Wilson, who we haven't talked
about yet, uh who has a chance to make
an impact for them, they've added, you
know, 18 guys over the last two years.
Um they're rebuilding the depth. Uh I'm
very excited to watch our offense when
it's at full strength. Uh I just I know
this team's not going to be at full
strength and they are still they've got
they've got 15 guys now, you know, like
they they used to have 12 guys, now
they've got 15 guys. like and I'm
excited about it, but I just can't I
can't, you know, unless they have
immaculate health, I can't bet on, you
know, on them being fully arrived yet.
But I like where they are. I mean, last
year I thought they were a five- win
team. This year I think they're an
eight- win team. Maybe next year they
can be a 10 or an 11 win team. They're
they're on the
>> Before we go, did you see the clip of
Buck Bucky Brooks and uh Daniel Jeremiah
fighting
>> uh fighting over Jordan Tyson or
fighting over what? They were fighting
over how many games Fernando Mendoza
would play and it got it got really
heated before we get before we become
Bucky and Daniel Jeremiah.
>> Where are you worried about the depth?
What like what spot specifically?
>> Um any starting offensive lineman uh
especially uh Banks, Foga or McCoy. Um
any receiver take a Tyson out of the
mix. Take Chase Young out of the mix.
Take Kaden Ellis out of the mix. Take
Kool-Aid McKinstry out of the mix. like
they still didn't address the secondary.
I'm just I I just feel like I'm really
excited to watch this team play when all
their starters are on the field. But I I
I don't I don't I Funny enough,
receivers is one of the few positions
that actually has depth now. Obviously,
if Tyler Chuck ever missed a game, but
I'm not I'm just This is more of my like
AI computer brain. I mean, if I have to
do a power rankings, New Orleans is
probably going to be like 20th in the
power rankings. They're not going to be
12th. I mean,
>> I think I got them at 10 wins, man. Like
I really do. And I think offensively I
think they're deep everywhere. Like very
deep.
>> Very deep. I mean look most teams if you
take out their their starting tackle
they're probably screwed. But I look at
it now and it's like hey look like they
got some tight ends that can block. They
could they could go to 12 if if Banks
gets hurt. You probably don't leave you
know Awesome Richards on a island
anymore because
>> you know you you can't like and you
don't have to. you have guys that can go
out there and can can actually solve the
problem a little bit more and it doesn't
maybe railroad your whole team. And if
you're leaning into that identity, I
think maybe you're okay there. Look, if
if McCoy gets hurt, I don't feel
terrible about Raiden's playing and and
Caesar shifting over to to center. I'm
okay with that. I I don't feel like it
railroads your season. I think we saw
last year that isn't necessarily a
pressure point, but you know, I feel
really good about their depth at wide
receiver, really good about their depth
at tight end, really good about their
depth at running back as long as Alvin's
on the team. Um, you know, obviously if
your quarterback gets hurt, your
season's probably over. Defensive end
has been remade a little bit. I'm
worried about the talent on defense, I
think, overall, but linebackers kind of
deep now. Defensive end, there's four
respectable players on that list. Uh,
potentially
cornerback. Yeah, you know, Kool-Aid
goes down. I'm okay playing Ike. I'm
worried about the slot. I, you know, I
don't know what Blackman's going to do,
and I can't really bet on Blackman all
the way. start to finish until I see him
do it. So, yeah, I I have a couple
concerns there overall, but I I think
this is a team that can absorb a couple
injuries on offense and still score. I
think they're going to score a lot of
points this year, man. Like, if you're
telling me Shuck is the same as last
year and you give them this offense, I I
think they find their way to it. Maybe
I'm I'm overhyped, but I was at nine
before and I feel really good about what
they did in this draft coming out of it.
I'm I'm going to sit at 10. Like I'm I'm
drinking I'm drinking uh you know it
might be flavor aid, but I'm drinking
it. And you know, I might have the wrong
stuff in my cup, but my cup's full right
now.
>> Yeah. Look, I'm hovering between eight
and nine. I'm at eight and a half, so
I'm not that far off. I'm just, you
know, I I'm just I'm just betting on the
state of the team. Like we, you know,
I'm being I'm being patient and
methodical.
Like I'd have to sketch it out. I don't
like anyone in the South better than
them. Um, but I also wouldn't pick any
NFC South team to win 10 games. Uh, I
I'm trying to look at the latest Vegas
total. I think the Saints are still at
seven and a half in Vegas, but I don't
know.
>> Here's the thing about the NFC, too.
Nobody they don't there's nobody that
can play quarterback in the whole
conference, basically.
>> Yes, true.
>> There like there are no quarterbacks.
So, if Tyler Shucks's good, like they
they're
>> I don't know. I like their position,
man. I like their position. They're all
in around them. I'm betting on,
>> you know,
>> I'm bet I'm betting on the uh the shock
upside, too. I mean, man,
>> they got a lot of guys around him right
now.
There's a lot on this offense right now.
Like, this offense should be really good
>> if you think he is.
>> Their run game, too, just just by
bringing everybody back and doing it
better than last season. Uh, I I think
they've got smart guys in the room who
are going to improve their run game just
through tweaking their scheme and and
obviously adding David Edwards and and
Travis Han to the mix.
>> Yeah, look, I might, like I said, I
might have Flavor Aid and Splenda and,
you know, come to find out, it's not
it's not what it should be, but I don't
know, man. I'm looking at it like I feel
good about where they're at right now.
>> It's probably somewhere between our two
takes, which would be nine. I'm at eight
and nine, but I'm also or maybe nine and
eight, like I said, hovering right
there, which is huge. If we had had this
conversation
12 months ago, we were like, you you
were going out to college games
throughout September and October
thinking they would have the number one
pick in the draft.
So, eight months ago, we did not think
they were they were that close to being
an 8 to 10 win team. and we both think
they're an eight to 10 win team right
now. They've they've arrived a lot
faster than than how bare bones they
were uh heading into last year's off
season and last year's season.
>> I mean, look, we just watched a team um
you know, with a quarterback and then
they went all in around the offense and
got to the Super Bowl uh that way. And
and you know, Kell Moore is going to be
Kell Moore's focus on the field, too.
So, I like that plus for the Saints. you
know, that's a good place for the the
coach to be looking. So, um yeah, I
mean, I feel I feel like they got a
chance, man. I feel like they got a
chance to to uh you know, get better
fast. And they got a lot on this this
offense. Like, it's crazy how much
different it is. Uh very, they went from
slow and sluggish kind of Chris L plus a
bunch of like slow and like sluggish
guys to just there's speed everywhere.
There's upside everywhere. David Ed
Edwards is on this team now. Like we
haven't even talked about him yet in
this. Like I I don't know. We'll see.
We'll see where it's at. You're probably
your sober take is probably
is what it is. But yeah, I mean like I
just I feel good about where they're at
right now. Uh all right, moving on.
Presented by Aaron Rose. This topic
presented by Aaron Rose. Tyrie Wilson
coming in the the trade for him. Um and
then they signed uh Anthony Jennings
this weekend as well or are going to
sign him probably whenever the uh period
opens up where it won't count against
the comp picks.
I like the Tyrie move for a fifth round
pick. I would have hated, you know,
obviously for a first round pick. No, I
think for a fifth round pick, if he
gives you four or five sacks, which he's
shown he's going to do damn near every
year, he kind of fits like if you kind
of lay everything out and the arcs and
the, you know, the the graphs and
everything like his curve kind of fits
right in with Carl Granderson's curve.
Fine. A fine player. I don't know that
he changes your your team overall, but
when you're chase young on Carl
Granderson, nothing else, I I I think he
I think he's a very very good addition
for this team. I really really like that
move.
>> I I mean, how can you not love it? I
mean, they didn't just trade a fifth
round pick for him either. They traded a
fifth round pick for him and a seventh
rounder and then they take TJ Hall in
the seventh round who they could have
they were discussing in the fifth round.
They said I actually saw a mock draft
where TJ Hall went in the third round.
So, I mean, it's basically like he was
cut by the Raiders and the Saints signed
him, you know, for the league m, you
know? I mean, like there is no risk to
this whatsoever. I I would do this all
the time. I think all teams should do
it. I don't know why the Raiders had to
give him away. I mean, he's incredibly
talented. He was the seventh pick in the
draft. Like, he's not getting arrested.
He's not getting hurt all the time.
Like, they just haven't been able to tap
into it. Uh, I mean, of course he could
be Isaiah Fosski and it could never
happen or Trevor Penning and it could
never happen. But when you can take a
look for free, take a look every single
time. And if all he's being asked to do
is play 20 pass rush snaps a game and
you've looked on film and you're like,
he does this one thing really well, so
we'll have him do this one thing. Great.
Like like there's no downside to this
whatsoever.
>> Yeah. And again, if he gives you four
sacks this year, that that that's a dub
right there off a pick 150. And one of
the other things I like about him too is
is like his rookie year was obviously
not very good at all. Very, very rough
rookie year. But over the last two
years, his win rate and his pressure
rate, like those two things have gotten
closer together. So like the first year
he was winning, but it wasn't becoming
pressure. Last two years like he's
winning and now it's becoming more more
turning into more pressure. And those
two numbers are very very similar to
Carl Granderson's on there. So you give
me like a guy that's just in the maybe
he's not grando, but if you give me a
guy that's in the same conversation as
him is that third defensive end. Yeah, I
think that's a very good place to be. I
think I think it's solid. I I still
think they're a little short there. I
think there's room for for more. Um, but
I like the move and even if he hits free
agency and dips, if your fifth round
pick, if they drafted a guy with pick
150 and in the final year of his
contract you gave him four sacks, I
like, "Yeah, that was a fine pick for
them." Like, I don't know where
Christian Boy was pick. Was he a six
round pick? Like, if Christian Boyd came
out and gave you a season that's the
equivalent of five sacks, uh, four
sacks, five sacks this year and then
he's done. Like, that would be all
right. Good for Boyd. Like, they they
ended up hitting on that pick. That's
how I'd feel about it. So, the answer is
a problem.
What I was going to say is funny is, and
then we said they took TJ Hall in the
seventh round. I kind of like this edge
from Central Michigan that they picked
up after the draft, too, who's a guy
they could have drafted if they kept
their pick. And they they get him, too.
I mean, there's some candidates there.
And you throw in Anthony Jennings.
>> And speaking of Anthony Jennings, that
brings us into our next topic presented
by Shaw Bear Insurance, the Airhart
Agency. If you're getting insurance,
make sure you call Shabar. Two things
here. The Saints are now covered at
defensive end. they got insurance at
that position. They could just go into
the season with what they got, right? I
mean, Cam's still out there. I think
they probably are still willing to bring
Cam back, but the,
>> you know, and just sheerely roster
construction, that's no longer a spot
where there's like a a open sore need at
that position. They have four guys that
if they went into the season with them
on the depth chart, it's a reasonable
depth chart. Anthony Jennings doesn't
give you a ton in the pass rush, but
he's a really good run stopper. Uh kind
of a guy that goes out, you can count on
this at the edge. Losing Cam and his
pass rush production, I think makes them
a worse team, but I don't know that, you
know, the leverage the leverage is fully
on the Saint side now, I think.
>> Well, they add they brought back Chris
Rump a couple of weeks ago, who was
their defensive end last year. So Tyrie
Wilson and Anthony Jennings are
theoretically competing for, you know,
being the guy to replace Jordan or if
they both earn spots on this team,
they're replacing Jordan and Rump. Um,
so yeah, sheer numbers, they don't have
a a a gaping hole there. Now, you know,
Cam Jordan obviously was more productive
uh and has been for a long time, even
even last year, um, than these guys have
been. So, I know if he decides to come
back, he's going to want to say, "I'm
still the, you know, I'm still the top
three defensive end on this team." And
those guys are all fighting for the
fourth spot. But I don't know if it
changes. I mean, I think I genuinely I
take the Saints at their word that the
the offer is still on the table if Cam
wants to come back. Um, but I think
they're prepared for Cam not to come
back now or at least, you know, they've
got the leverage for Cam not to come
back. Their offer is not going up at
this point. That's
>> that that's all I'm saying is I I don't
think I think there was a scenario where
they could have ended up in the like the
oh got to go throw all the like
whatever.
>> I still think whatever Cam's asking just
just pay it for God's sakes like or or
just come come up a little bit and just
get it done just on the
>> longer than it needed to.
>> I don't understand this one. It's still
confusing to me. I think they did what
they had to do. You got to build out the
team. You got to build for for the
future. You got Tyreek Wilson evaluate
him. You got first shot at keeping them.
Anthony Jennings, get them in here. Look
at them. You got first shot at keeping
them. Fill out with some veteran guys. I
I I think these are all the moves they
should have made. I didn't think that
they were after after Christian Miller
got picked. I did not think we were
going to end up in a scenario where on
Monday we were like they're in a fine
position at this spot. I thought they
were absolutely screwed. They looked at
uh Tibido. We had mentioned it back in
February. They were looking at him. I
think that started out as a player for
player trade. Then I think the Giants
wanted a third round pick.
I'm totally fine with them getting
Tyreek Wilson for a fifth. Feel like
those guys are both kind of in the same
bucket a little bit. Um
pay less, get a guy. Um I like I like
the outcome probably. I think I you know
I don't have a strong take for either
one of them. I think they both have been
a little bit disappointing for their
teams. Um, so yeah, I mean I I I just
didn't see it I didn't see it ending up
here. Like when they didn't get an edge
rusher, I thought maybe the uh Thibido
trade would would happen. Then I got
strong signals like as that started
getting reported that like yeah, this
isn't going to go down like that that
trade's not going to happen. Like they
want way too much. Um yeah, I I just
didn't think I didn't think we'd be
talking about it like this today.
>> Yeah, I I'm still 5050 on whether Cam
comes back. And if Camp comes back,
whether whether he can beat these guys
out, I I think it's entirely possible.
But I just
>> beat him out. I think he probably beats
him out if he comes back.
>> He's he's held his uh he's held his
ground even longer than I expected.
I don't know what's going to happen
here. I really don't. I
>> He want to come back now.
>> I know. That's the thing. I think their
offer is still on the table to him, but
if he hasn't taken it now and they added
these guys, like if he's started to
think about
other options, whether that's another
team or life after, I don't know. I
mean, I just don't know. It's already
lasted longer than I expected it to.
>> Yeah, I agree. Um, Alvin, it looks like
I think
>> I feel closer to Alvin being back on
this team today than I have in a long
time because
>> absolutely not draft a running back.
>> Then Mickey Lumis said
in answer to an Alvin question, he
didn't answer directly. He said, "We'll
see what happens there. You know, we
still have talks to have there, but we
didn't go into this draft thinking we
needed a running back or a running back
wasn't a need for us going into this
draft." Did that coded mean something?
And then they cut Evan Hull today. Not
like Evan Hull was gonna stop Alvin from
being there, but I don't think you cut
Evan Hull if you think you're cutting
Alvin tomorrow. So I mean I just maybe
maybe it's all systems go with Alvin
Chimera again. I don't know.
>> I don't know. It's interesting. Yeah, I
feel like that's flipped a little bit.
It's it flipped. I you know it was it
was it felt like Cam was the more sure
coming back. Alvin felt
>> Yeah.
>> Boy, this is kind of crazy. I I still
think the album situation bears
monitoring. It's still very weird and a
lot has been said and I think what
hasn't been said has been important is
what's been said too just in terms of
how how that's playing out. I don't
know. It's very it's that very
fascinating. Very fascinating. The way
they've talked about Alvin as if he's a
free agent has been insane to me. Like
the whole thing's just very wild to me.
I can't wait to see what happens there.
It's going to be interesting. Uh but
that that should be resolving sooner
than later. You you'd think
>> what an amazing weapon Alvin Chimera is
going to be on this offense that we've
talked about that now has so many
options and he's like oh and Alvin
Chimera. We are very very recently
removed from when it was all they have
is Alvin Chimera.
>> Yeah. Yeah. It was like Alvin and Yeah.
Alvin and everybody else. Like that was
it. Alvin and Chris in the in the world.
Now they got all these guys and it's
just like holy crap.
Everybody's going to be so much better
and they're way better with Alvin on the
team. All right, we're going to hit a
quick break. We'll be right back with
the Get Gordon question of the day.
>> Are you ready to buy your first home
wondering if now's the right time to
refinance? Or maybe you're thinking
about getting into real estate. Whatever
play you're trying to run, the pros at
mortgage bros.money have the game plan.
If you are a first-time buyer, the
mortgage bros will break down every loan
program, help you build a budget that
works, and even check if you qualify for
100% financing or down payment
assistance. They'll guide you every step
of the way. Because buying your first
home shouldn't feel like a Hail Mary.
Heard that rates have dropped and
thinking it's time to refi? Don't just
guess. Get real answers. The mortgage
bros will review your situation for free
and tell you if it's time to make a move
or keep waiting for an even better rate.
And if you're ready to start investing
in real estate, don't let that old 20%
down myth stop you. The bros can show
you a home hack that might get you up to
three doors to rent with little to no
money down. Here's the best part. The
mortgage bros work with you for free.
You'll never pay them a penny. They're
not bankers. They're brokers. That means
if your loan doesn't close, they don't
get paid. So, they're just as invested
in getting you approved as you are.
Because let's be honest, signing up for
a 30-year loan without a pro on your
team is like trying to run the offense
without a playbook. You don't need to
know every role in the mortgage game.
Your pros already do. So, go to mortgage
bros.money. That's mortgage bros.money.
And let the bros be your pros. I got
hurt in a car wreck. Why should I get
Gordon?
>> Because when you're hurt, you need
money. And I fight for the people of
Southeast Louisiana every day. I got a
client who injured their neck in a car
wreck $250,000.
Another client was hit by a big truck
and needed back surgery. I got them
$700,000 and they deserved every single
penny. That's what I'm talking about.
Why wouldn't I get Gordon? If you've
been hurt in a car wreck, just call me
New Orleans. Get it done.
>> Call 50480088.
>> If you watch our show, you already know
the work that RV Masters does. They did
our van last offseason. I went up there.
I said, "Hey, look. I need power for
eight or nine hours. I need AC for eight
or nine hours, and I need everything I
need to run a broadcast from this van.
I'm going to drop it off and I want you
to take care of it." And they said, "All
right, cool. We got you." I went back up
a couple weeks later. Job's done. Looks
amazing. Works amazing. Went through a
whole entire season, not a single issue,
which is absolutely unbelievable to me.
They'll do whatever you need. They dream
bigger than you dream, and they can make
your wild dreams come to life. They have
preventative maintenance. They have
service packages for your RVs, your AC,
your generators. They specialize in
solar and lithium upgrades, satellite
TV, and Starlink. If you wreck your
vehicle, they'll get you fixed, too.
Whatever you need, they got you. That's
rv-masters.com.
They'll get you right. Whether you're a
local New Orleian or a fan in town for
the game, get your pre and postgame
fired up at Aaron Rose, local chaos, and
local love for the black and gold. Wake
up and live with daily drink specials,
mimosas, screwdrivers, bloody maryries,
and hot or frozen Irish coffees. All
just three or four dollars between 10 am
to 2 pm. Aaron Rose, half a block from
Bourbon Street in the French Quarter,
811 Ki Street. Attention football fans,
don't let pest and termites invade your
home field. Trust the team at Red Pest
Solutions to tackle those unwelcome
visitors. Call the red man today for
unbeatable pest and termite control.
Score peace with no pest. Visit
redpest.com. That's reddpst.com.
Welcome back to New Orleans. Football
presented by Loft 18. It's now time for
the get Gordon question of the day
presented by Gordon Mccernin injury
attorneys. A lot of talk today about
today yesterday uh about consensus
boards like the stupidest like this is
one of these topics that like goes way
too far and everybody gets like dug in
and no one wants to talk about a census
like sensibly. But
>> let's start at the top.
>> Yeah.
consensus board verse scouting versus
team versus what's your what's your take
on this whole great debate?
>> Okay. Well, I have two answers to this
and first is of course like John Lynch
is the one taking the most heat. The
49ers are are the team that doesn't
follow the consensus board and and
they're having horrible drafts. The the
Saints are are low on those lists too
from following the consensus board. And
I' I've used this line a million times
over the last 10 years. If Jeff Ireland
quit the Saints today and started a
website tomorrow, his big board would be
everyone's like favorite big board.
They'd be like, "This is Jeff Ireland."
Like everything. He's he's a genius. And
he'd go on the radio and he'd tell you
his thought process and you'd be like,
"This guy's sharper than Daniel Jeremiah
and Mel Kyper and Todd McShet." And
you'd be like just one guy working for
the team. That's probably true of all 32
teams. Daniel Jeremiah was just like a
one of many scouts for the Ravens. And
because he has that credibility, you
take him seriously as a draft analyst.
So the guys working for teams are more
qualified or equally qualified as any
Dne Bugler, Todd McShet, anybody that
does this, Jordan Reed, etc., etc., etc.
However,
what those guys all do, the good ones,
Dane Bugler, Todd Mcshay, Daniel
Jeremiah, who am I forgetting? Mel
Kyper, you know, uh, Field Yates, all
these guys, is they talk to guys who
work for teams. They have great sources.
They educate themselves. They watch tape
and then they talk to all the people who
know what they're doing and they say,
"Who we missing?" And they're saying,
"You got you have that guy way too low.
You have that guy way too high." They
talk to probably people from all 32
teams. They learn what the league is
thinking. So by the time Dane Burgler
puts out the Beast, that has a ton of
information, real information from real
teams, from real scouts. So, if a team
is zagging from what all those other
people have, they are zagging from what
the rest of the league has.
>> Yeah. It's so crazy to me, man. Like,
people are like, "Oh, well, the media,
nobody would hire him." Any team would
hire Dane today if they could pay him
enough to hire him. It's just those jobs
don't pay much. Like, they don't pay a
lot. And Dne isn't going to take a lower
paying job and then just try to, you
know, work his way up or what. Like,
he's got a good job. He makes a lot of
money. He He's comfortable. play. Daniel
Jeremiah would probably go back and work
for a team today if they offered him a
highpaying like a GM job, but
>> got a GM job.
>> Yeah, he's like he's like working in
that role. But yeah, the the craziest
thing to me is most of the draft takes
are informed. A lot of us aren't sitting
here just blindly ranking a 100 players.
A lot of them are informed. You'll see
people like a player and then all of a
sudden they like somebody else more.
They didn't re-educate their their
opinion from like watching every game
during the fall. They re-educated their
opinion because somebody with the weight
of saying these things has told them
that their opinion is wrong. And then
you're like, well, okay, maybe I do like
this receiver better than this receiver.
You know, like that's usually what
happens. Like what am I missing? Well,
this is what you're missing. Oh, okay.
Like so, you know, you don't always take
someone's word for it, but a lot of
times, yes, that's how it goes from one
set of rankings from people that have
spent the whole season watching and
usually that's the lower level scouts in
January. You guys have heard me say this
100 times. Then people get involved and
you see the rankings change and now the
position coaches are involved. Now the
the people that were focused on the NFL
season, the GMs and all that are
involved and then all of a sudden, you
know, Mail Lemon goes from pick five to
pick 20 and that's how it happens is and
then everyone, you know, start shifting
and you see everybody kind of be in the
same place. But nobody nobody's really
doing it blind. Even if you look at the
consensus rankings to how teams draft
and I seen a chart of like the wins
above replacement metric, it's the same
line to about player 100. And then in
the middle rounds, the NFL does way
better than the consensus board. And
that's usually because A, these are only
the only people that people are
familiarizing themselves with. B, most
of the conversations you're going to
have are going to be on guys that are
taken in the first three rounds. Most
people aren't calling up and having very
detailed conversations about the fifth
rounders. I bet Dane Bugler is, but the
consensus board is made up of like 40
people, you know? It's just like
everybody that puts it out that kind of
has a little bit of weight. So, most
people aren't that sourced to have that
level of conversation of like what's
going to happen in the sixth round. Like
a a lot of them don't have the knowledge
to conduct those things and b they just
don't you know there there's a element
of I'm going to have valuable
conversations with the bullets I have
and I'm not going to fire a bunch. But
like Dane Bugler, yes. And yeah, like as
you were saying, these conversations end
up being with you you you find people
that are doing the same things every
day. It's a very lonely pursuit of just
sitting there trying to figure out
what's going on with the NFL draft and
you end up finding your community a
little bit and okay, hey, I I just spent
an hour watching, you know, this fourth
round receiver and there there's just
people that are doing the same things
and you end up finding each other and
having these conversations. That's how
mock drafts come together. It's how
information flows, all that stuff. Yeah,
I mean it's it isn't like this great
divide. It's people that are on similar
paths and Yeah. I mean most of the stuff
is informed opinion.
>> Informed opinion. Yeah.
>> Informed opinion.
>> Not just guy in his basement.
>> What? And as you get better at it. Yeah.
You're you're more and more informed. I
I would love to see like just take a
take a Todd McShay
and just cut him off from the world. no
internet access. It all you could do is
just straight up do it.
>> I would love to see that versus that.
But that that isn't how any of this
happens. None of it happens like that.
Yeah.
>> Nobody's like really there's a few
people now. There are a few people I see
out there and they they will have wildly
different takes and they will get smoked
and then you see them retweet something
from three years ago and it's like damn
that guy like did a pure process and
like he he cooked everybody. Like you
see some of those now and then but most
people aren't doing that. most people
aren't doing it and it's just I don't
know what the better way is but you know
I think you want to have a reflection of
what's gonna happen in in in the
process. Um, and there's Yeah, I agree
with this, but whatever. But you do see
it. You like doing this, you see how
people, you could tell when somebody had
a conversation with somebody,
>> right? No question. And uh, first of
all, Matt Miller, we should also shout
out friend of the show. Didn't list him
when we're listing all those names.
Lance, a lot of other guys that uh, uh,
we're leaving out. But the other the
second part of this conversation is all
right. So we have agreed there is some
legitimacy to the consensus board
because they are collecting information
from teams building their board. So what
do you think about the teams that Zach
like I mean Pton Turner comes to mind?
Nobody had Payton Turner in the first
round. The Saints took Pton Turner in
the first round and he flopped. Uh so
does that mean you should never stray
from the big board? I'm trying to think
of success stories where somebody uh
took somebody who nobody had somewhere
and then they were right and everybody
else was wrong. But like, do you want
your team to shut themselves off from
the world, do it in a vacuum, only talk
to the players and not look? Do you want
them drafting based only on their
grades? Or do you want your team trying
to get a peg on what the rest of the NFL
universe is doing and then be like, I
don't think we have to take this guy
until round three? Like, should teams
factor in consensus ports?
Well, I think I think like the John
Lynch thing here is they felt like they
probably had everyone beat to the the
the Mississippi receiver, the old Miss
uh dribbling like
>> Yeah.
>> But if John Lynch was out here and
they're a team that that people
historically have not been able to get a
beat on what they're going to do. I
remember when they had the the
quarterback pick and they obviously blew
it, but nobody knew what they were going
to do. Everybody was wrong on what they
were going to do. They're a team that
plays their cards close to their chest.
And I think part of the reason for that
is is that John Lynch didn't have to
lick any boots to get to where he is. He
doesn't owe anyone any favors. He he
probably doesn't have a ton of
relationships out there with people. He
doesn't owe anyone anything. Kellum
Moore is very much the same way. He got
there cleanly without having to, hey,
get my name out there, let me play the
game, all this stuff. So, there aren't a
lot of leaks on the Saints. Mickey Lumis
doesn't know anybody anything. Trust
like we try very hard to find out what
they're doing. And over the years, we
figured out, you know, ways to kind of
figure it out, but it's beating around
the bush, man. Like, you got to kick a
lot of bushes and find out kind of what
everybody else is doing and then try to
reverse engineer what they're doing. Try
to make a best guess and you kind of
there's there's been enough runway with
what Mickey does and what Jeff Ireland
does that you kind of figure out what
their what their players are and you as
you think about it more and more, it's
like, all right, like this is how it's
going to happen. Here's the thing with
them is is if they had spent a lot of
time telling people Peyton Turner is a
first round pick. Pton Turner is
reflected in that thing. They don't tell
anyone what they're doing. So they
actually surprised all of us. Like
everybody in the world Pton Turner came
out of nowhere. No one saw that coming
day of the draft. It was like, "Oh, Pton
Turner might go higher than you think."
But like if the agents not tipping
anything and if it's like, "Oh, wow.
They're going to take my guy three
rounds higher than anybody thought." He
he's probably not going to spill the
beans and and ruin it for his client
because that could well, you know, f
this guy. We're not taking him that. So,
if that leak isn't there and if John
Lynch or Mickey Lumis isn't out here
telling everybody what they're going to
do, that guy sits there. But if Lynch
had been telling everybody or who's
their director of college, Josh
Williams, I think like if Josh Williams
had been telling everybody or if
Shanahan had been telling everyone and
there were all these leaks coming out,
he's a second round guy on these boards,
but they actually protected it. Oh,
>> people get pissed when it leaks, but
then they're pissed when it breaks the
consensus and it's just
>> the the consensus could be easily
manipulated if if they were just in
enough influential people's ears because
that's how we know how it happens. Like,
oh man, everybody has this guy. Is this
guy actually a second rounder? Like, is
he actually going to go here? Um, yeah,
he might. And and look, then if the
Giant or if the 49ers don't take them,
we're talking about a huge fall. And I
think that's how huge falls happen, too,
is that there's these expectations. I
could set and then something else
happens and that might just be one or
two teams that are in on a guy at that
point and nobody else is and they've
told people.
>> Yeah.
>> But then something else happens and they
they zigg and now oh my god he was
supposed to go in the second round and
now he's sitting there in the fourth.
Yeah.
>> Like that's how these things happen.
>> It's it's interesting. But you know
we're here to educate you.
>> Yeah. Yeah. We are like it is a like you
could make yourself not look wild by
telling everyone but then you might not
get your player. Like it's just kind of
it's just kind of interesting, man. It
really is like if all of a sudden if
everyone's talking about like streaming
being a second rounder now, teams might
go back and evaluate, re-evaluate, and
they might be like, "Wait, you know
what? This actually is like we missed
this."
>> Yeah, you can make it. You can you can
manifest it.
>> Yeah, you can. Mickey said that before
like you know Yeah. these trade rumors
like it's one of those things that
become self-fulfilling because everyone
starts talking about it and then
something happens. Yeah. So, it's just
kind of interesting how how all this
stuff works out and there is a gross
amount of group think and I think it
goes from both ways. I think it's the
league and I think it's media. Um, it's
just kind of how it's just it is what it
is, man. Like I I I think people want to
be people actually want to be closer to
that consensus than not because most
people I've been on the soap box the
whole draft season. Like a lot of people
are afraid of getting fired
>> and you don't want to be, you know, if
you're a weak GM, you don't want to be
the person with the headline of, you
know, your owners reading it the next
day and wait, they took this guy 90
picks higher.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. You don't want to be the team
getting an F uh on your on your draft
grades. You don't want to be you don't
want to be in the Jacksonville position
right now, you know, with a you it's
just you don't you don't want people
talking about you like that depending on
who your owner is. So, um, you know, I
think people want to be closer to it. I
I respect the people that are willing to
go out and just Jacksonville did a lot
of things people didn't see coming. I
respect, you know, San Fran's been wrong
too many times, but I I respect people
that are willing to take these shots,
but man, you take that shot, you better
be right. You can miss when you follow
consensus and the blowback isn't as
great. Oh, well, everybody thought FYI
was going to be good, you know? But
like, what are they doing with Payton
Turner? Like, it's just it's a different
>> It's a good point. It's a different
take. Um, all right. That's going to do
it for today's show. We'll talk to you
next time.